[Gon] Ging is spelled G-I-N-G.
[Bisky] Oh, I see!
So "Nigg" is an anagram.
[Gon] My guess is that
when I was just a baby,
I must have come here with Ging.
Maybe this was his way
of trying to tell me…
if I'm ready to give up everything I have
and go find him,
then I have to get strong enough
to clear the game.
Well, what are you planning to do
once you find Ging?
That's easy.
-I'll introduce him to Killua.
-Huh?
I'll tell him he's
my best friend in the world!
Accompany on!
Nigg!
[opening theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[singer singing in English]
REUNION X AND X UNDERSTANDING
[Gon gasps]
[Killua] Wait. Is that Gon's…
G-Ging.
-[ground crunches]
-[gasps]
[both grunt]
In my mouth is a roulette
containing the numbers one
all the way through nine.
You get a different weapon
for each number on the wheel.
I am the great mad clown, Crazy Slots!
Hope you get something good!
[babbles]
Four!
[man] Damn, bad roll.
[Crazy Slots] Shut up!
Be grateful, you idiot!
[gunshots]
[Killua] What the…
an ant?
-[man] Are you hurt?
-[both gasp]
[gun clicks]
[Killua] Is it him? Is that Ging?
[gasps]
-This isn't Ging.
-What?
Hang on.
What was that all about? Tell us!
First you knock us down.
Then you start firing at us!
Stop messing around!
[man] "Messing around"?
Quite the opposite.
If I hadn't opened fire,
you both would have been attacked.
[Killua] Yeah, by what,
that stupid ant you shot?
[growls]
[yells]
What is this?
[man] You fool!
[Gon gasps]
That was no ordinary ant.
It's a Chimera Ant.
[Killua] A what?
[man] An aggressive, carnivorous insect
that's been designated
quarantine level one.
They even attack humans
from time to time.
[Killua gasps]
You boys didn't realize it,
but you were standing
right in front of their nest.
If I hadn't fired the moment I did,
an army of Chimera Ants
would have consumed
the both of you by now.
[Gon gasps]
I feel like this has happened before.
[man sighs]
Don't worry. It's not serious.
It's antiseptic. Use it.
-[Gon gasps]
-[Crazy Slots] What?
Give me a break. Is that it?
Come on. Let's go wild, man!
Ah, shut up, and go away already.
The two of you should leave as well.
Damn it.
Now I'll have to start over
from the beginning.
Well, at least the nest was destroyed.
Damn it, and now
I've got this pointless kill to my credit.
[Gon gasps]
Huh?
Hmm?
[dramatic music playing]
Damn it, and now I've got this
pointless kill to my credit.
Hey, are you…
Back when I was younger,
are you the one who saved me?
Wait. When?
[Gon] On Whale Island.
I'd stumbled onto a foxbear
with her cub in the forest.
-[man] Whale Island?
-[Gon] Remember?
You said you had a pointless kill
to your credit because of what I did.
Oh, yeah. I remember.
I never thought
I'd run into you again here.
You sure have grown up, Gon.
-[Killua] Hmm?
-[Gon gasps]
But how do you know my name?
I heard it from your dad, Ging.
[Killua] What?
[Gon] So you know Ging, old man?
Old ma--
[sighs]
Yeah, but my name is Kite.
Ging was actually my master.
[both gasp]
[serene music playing]
[waves crashing]
[creature hisses]
Ah, so both of you are
Pro Hunters, too. Is that right?
Yep. Are you one, sir?
Just call me Kite.
You're my master's son,
so don't be so formal.
Okay. So you're one, too, Kite?
I am.
Master Ging's the one who
made me a first-class Hunter.
He was my teacher and my benefactor.
See, if I had never met Ging,
I'd be dead now,
rotting in the back alley
of a slum, probably.
[man 1] Hey, wait up!
[man 2] Stupid brat!
He just stole my bread!
That's all I could find!
[man 1] Yeah, well, not if we can help it!
[man 2 grunts]
[man 3] Whoa!
Huh?
[dog growls]
[man 2] That's my bread!
[man 1] You're not getting away
with it this time, punk!
[gasping] Ow!
What the hell is this?
What are you… Stop it!
-[dog growling]
-[men gasp]
[dog barking]
[men sigh]
[wind blowing]
[water dripping]
[footsteps echoing]
[light crackling]
[Kite gasps]
[Ging] Uh, hey.
So do you live down here with these guys?
It looks fun!
[insects chirping]
That was it?
That's how you met Ging?
Yeah.
Ging told me once
that every single Hunter
is well liked by animals.
He also told me I had potential,
so that piqued my interest.
So you were his student?
Once I forced him to teach me.
He's not very fond of anything
that causes him too much hassle,
so I was never his student
in any official capacity.
But I suppose I can be a little stubborn,
so I just hounded him 'til he caved.
A while after that,
I started to develop my Nen,
and he started teaching me to hunt.
As a result, I passed the Hunter exam
without much trouble.
But Master Ging still wasn't satisfied.
There was another hurdle I had to clear.
Can you guess what that hurdle was?
[Gon] I think I might know.
Yeah?
[Gon] No. I definitely know.
If I know Ging, he probably told you
that he wants you to try and catch him.
[Kite chuckles]
Right. That's it exactly.
I knew it!
I thought that was it.
But as far as I knew,
Ging was the absolute greatest
Hunter in the whole world.
It would be the most difficult hunt ever.
There were no clues
or leads to start with.
Not only that,
there were no rumors of his whereabouts,
or sightings of him either.
It seemed like he'd managed to
completely erase his existence.
[Killua] Like a superpowered
form of Zetsu?
And then?
What happened next?
[Kite] I was struggling,
grasping for anything
that might help me find him,
so I went to his hometown,
to Whale Island.
And that was when I first met you, Gon.
[Gon gasps]
[Kite] But back then,
I didn't realize you were Ging's son.
I had no idea.
I didn't learn that
until I had finally found Ging
and told him about what had
happened on Whale Island.
[wind blowing]
[Ging] That was my kid.
His name's Gon.
[Kite gasps]
[Ging] Thanks for clobbering him.
Some things are just common sense,
like avoiding foxbear territory
while they're raising their young. Heh.
[Gon gasps]
The fact that I went to Whale Island,
or that I met you there,
none of that seemed to surprise him.
It was almost as if he'd expected it.
Looking back now,
I think everything that's happened
has gone according to Ging's plan.
You're saying he set all this up?
Well, I can't prove it.
[Gon] You may be right.
Huh?
Razor was there waiting for me,
Dwun and List, too.
Razor and Dwun?
Yeah. It was in a game
called "Greed Island,"
but it's kind of a long story.
We got inside the game,
and Razor told me he was waiting for me.
Ging told him to.
[Ging] One day,
my son's going to come here.
When he does, don't hold back.
Ha! Fine. Does that mean
that I can kill him?
Don't underestimate him.
He is my kid.
I'm counting on you. Thanks, Razor.
[Gon] Ging created "Greed Island"
with the help of ten of his close friends.
Dwun and List were two of 'em.
Oh! And Razor.
He's also one of Ging's friends.
Well, anyway, those three were all there,
just waiting for me.
When I learned that, I realized something.
If that was Ging's big plan all along,
for me to go there and meet his friends,
then I wonder if meeting all the others,
people like Bisky and everybody else…
Well, that might have been
part of his plan, too, right?
[Killua] And if that's really the case,
then it's also possible
that Ging wanted you
to meet Kite here,
so he helped to make it happen.
[Gon] Think so?
-Hey, that's right!
-Hmm?
[Gon] You must have
spent time on Greed Island
at some point, haven't you?
[Kite] Me?
Yeah. And when you went,
did you register under the name of Nigg?
[Kite] Nigg? No, I don't
recall that name. Wait.
I do remember Ging taking me
inside a game a while back,
now that you mention it.
I knew it!
[Kite] "Greed Island."
Yes, I believe that's what it was called.
But I can't remember if I used an alias.
That's gotta be it!
Ging must have had you register
the name Nigg back then!
Damn it! He got me good! Ohh!
And you were convinced you'd meet him.
[Gon groaning in frustration]
[Elena] Are you sure
that was the right decision, Ging?
[Ging] So, can you make it
so that using magnetic force
will send Gon to me,
while using Accompany
will send him to Kite?
Yes, I suppose so.
But why do you want me to do that?
[Ging] If he uses magnetic force
to see me on his own,
I guess I'm willing to meet him.
But if he's a wimp who needs
to bring his friends along,
forget it.
Why is he a wimp
if he brings his friends?
I don't understand that.
[Ging gasps]
Never mind that! Just do it!
More people would just
make you self-conscious, right?
Please, just shut up, and do what I asked.
Honestly, Ging is so weird.
He's both shy and stubborn.
I feel sorry for Gon.
[fire crackling]
[Kite] I see.
So the real reason
that "Greed Island" was created
was to provide you boys
with the type of training you needed.
[Killua] No, it was only for Gon, really.
I've pretty much been along
for the ride the whole time.
But that might have been
part of Ging's plan, too, don't you think?
Even me? Not likely.
More like impossible.
But it appears
that all of us meeting here
was no mere coincidence.
[Killua] Yeah. I agree.
There's gotta be some
deeper meaning to all this.
Like what?
Like Razor waited inside the game
so he could help make you stronger.
And if that's the case,
then it would make sense
that Ging has some role
for Kite to play, too.
A role, huh?
You said
that your final test was to find Ging.
-Is that right?
-[Kite] Yeah.
That sounds like a pretty daunting task.
The best Hunters in the world
are masters of hunting, sure,
but they're also masters
of concealing themselves,
yet you still found him.
[Gon] Uh-huh. I think so, too.
Once your final test
was completed, Kite,
Ging must have made his choice.
You were worthy of handling this.
"Handling this"? Wait. What?
Oh, come on.
Gotta walk you through it?
Basically…
Thanks for clobbering him.
[Kite] Hey, Gon.
[Gon] Hmm?
[Kite] Want me to tell you
where Ging is right now?
No, thanks. I'll find him myself.
That's a good answer.
So anyway, tell me all about Ging.
I wanna hear every story
that you've got about him!
[creature chewing]
[Gon] You're kidding me.
How to help two-headed wolves
with breeding?
Ging's really involved in that stuff, too?
[Kite] Of course he is.
Ging is involved with a wide
range of Hunter activities.
He's never formally applied for it,
because he doesn't want
to spend the time or energy,
but he's as qualified
as a triple star Hunter.
A triple star?
Stars are given to Hunters
who perform extraordinary tasks.
Those responsible
for historical discoveries,
or global achievements
are awarded three stars.
There are fewer than ten
of these Hunters in the world.
The title "Triple Star Hunter"
is reserved for the very best.
Wow. So Ging's as good as
the best Hunters in the world?
Awesome!
[Killua] So Kite's a Hunter
who's earned Ging's respect.
But that isn't all he's done.
Ging is also famous
for discovering the Lurka Ruins,
not to mention the Kongo Gold Vein.
Really? I've heard of that one!
The Lurka Ruins, I mean.
[narrator] Kite, Ging's student,
his meeting with Gon and Killua
was a clear indication
that a brand-new adventure
was about to begin.
Meanwhile, on the southern
shores of the Balsa Islands,
on the Yorbian Continent,
a prologue to an unparalleled fear
was steadily,
yet ever so quietly unfolding.
[creature] These creatures
simply aren't enough,
no matter how many I eat,
but I can't move.
I mustn't be hasty.
I must focus on recovering my energy.
I must heal
before I can take the next step.
[chewing]
I have a duty to fulfill.
I have to give birth to the King!
I am the Queen.
[closing theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[dramatic music playing]
[inaudible]
[Gon] Next time, "Unease and Sighting."
Are you uneasy, Killua?
[Killua] You're embarrassing me.
[singer singing in Japanese]